Fritz Kreisler Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music, 1845-1966 (Box 1-13, 23)
  - Kreisler as Arranger (Box 5-13)
    - Compositions Attributed to a Single Composer (Box 6-13)
      - Schumann, Robert
        - [Fantasie, violin & orchestra, op. 131, C major; arr.], Kreisler holograph full score in pencil; 69 p.; At end of music: Berlin, 9 Juli 1936; Uniform title: Fantasie, violin & orchestra, op. 131, C major; arr. (Box-folder 9/3)
        - Fantasie in C dur, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil with annotations; 25 p.; On cover: Joseph Joachim zugeeignet; Uniform title: Fantasie, violin & orchestra, op. 131, C major; arr. (Box-folder 9/4)
        - Fantasie in C dur, Copyist's score for violin and piano (27 p.) and violin part (9 p.), in ink with holograph annotations in pencil; Uniform title: Fantasie, violin & orchestra, op. 131, C major; arr. (Box-folder 9/5)
        - Phantasie in C dur, Copyist's score for violin and piano, in ink with pasteovers; 25 p.; Uniform title: Fantasie, violin & orchestra, op. 131, C major; arr. (Box-folder 9/6)
      - Sibelius, Jean
        - Concerto in D minor, op. 47 New York: International Music Company, 1942., Printed score for violin and piano (36 p.) and violin part (15 p.); Arranged by A. Gretchaninoff; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, op. 47, D minor; arr. (Box-folder 13/9)
        - Violin concerto in D minor, op. 47, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink and pencil; 39 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin & orchestra, op. 47, D minor; arr. (Box-folder 9/7)
        - Violinkonzert, D-moll Berlin: Paul Juon, 1933., Printed violin part with pencil annotations and paste-over in finale ;15 p.; Edited by Ossip Schnirlin; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, op. 47, D minor; arr. (Box-folder 13/10)
      - Spohr, Louis
        - Violin-Konzerte Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano with extensive alterations in pencil; 22 p.; Versehen von Ferdinand David und Friedrich Hermann; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 8, op. 47. In Form einer Gesangscene; arr. (Box-folder 9/8)
      - Strauss, Johann
        - Man lebt nur einmal. Walzer, Strauss holograph piano score in ink; 5 p. (Box-folder 13/11)
      - Tartini, Giuseppe
        - Le trille du diable (Teufelstrillersonate), Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; 16 p.; On cover: Meinem lieben Freunde Dr. B. Pollack herzlichst zugeeignet; Uniform title: Sonata, violin & continuo, G minor; arr. (Box-folder 9/9)
        - The devil's trill (Le trille du diable) New York: Charles Foley, 1932., Printed violin part; 9 p.; Uniform title: Sonata, violin & continuo, G minor; arr. (Box-folder 9/10)
      - Vieuxtemps, Henri
        - Zweites Concert, op. 19 Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano with extensive pasteovers and alterations in pencil; 31 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 2, op. 19, F# minor; arr. (Box-folder 10/1)
        - Concerto no. 2, F# minor, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink, incomplete; 8 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 2, op. 19, F# minor. Fragment; arr. (Box-folder 10/2)
        - Concerto no. 4, D minor, Kreisler holograph full score in pencil; 137 p.; On title page: scored by Fritz Kreisler in 1907; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 4, op. 31, D minor; arr. (Box-folder 10/3)
        - Concerto in D minor for violin New York: G. Schirmer, 1921., Printed score for violin and piano with extensive pasteovers and alterations in ink and pencil; 55 p.; On front free endpaper: arranged by F. Kreisler, 1907; At end of music: Fritz Kreisler, Jan. 5, 1940; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 4, op. 31, D minor; arr. (Box-folder 10/4)
      - Viotti, Giovanni Battista
        - Berühmte Violin-Concerte von Kreutzer, Rode und Viotti Leipzig: C. F. Peters, n.d., Printed score for violin and piano with holograph pasteovers and inserts in pencil; 24 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 22, A minor; arr. (Box-folder 10/6)
        - [Concerto, violin, no. 22, A minor; arr.], Kreisler holograph full score in pencil; 110 p.; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 22, A minor; arr. (Box-folder 10/5)
        - Cadenzas for the Viotti concerto no. 22 in A minor, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil and ink; [7 p.]; Uniform title: Concerto, violin, no. 22, A minor. Cadenza; arr. (Box-folder 10/7)
      - Vivaldi, Antonio
        - XII Sonate Milano: Istituto di Alta Cultura, n.d., Printed score??; 59 p.; Laid in: note from Vittorio Daneu to Fritz Kreisler; Uniform title: Sonata, violin & contrabass, no. 12 (Box-folder 13/12)
      - Wagner, Richard
        - Siegfried-Paraphrase Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1909., Printed score for voice and piano (11 p.) and violin part (3 p.); Arranged by August Wilhelmj; Uniform title: Der Ring des Nibelungen. Siegfried; arr. (Box-folder 13/14)
      - Whelpley, Benjamin
        - My love is ever mine New York: G. Schirmer, 1902., Printed piano-vocal score; 5 p.; On cover, in ink: An Herrn Crown Prince Otto Von Hafesburg[?] c/o Concertmeister Fritz Kreisler, Stadt Theater, Viena[sic], Austria; Uniform title: Four songs, op. 5. No. 4, My love is ever mine (Box-folder 13/13)
      - Wieniawski, Henri
        - Caprice - tarantella, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in ink; 3 p.; Uniform title: Etudes-caprices, violin, op. 18, no. 4; arr. (Box-folder 10/8)
        - Airs russes, Kreisler holograph score for violin and piano, in pencil; [8 p.]; Uniform title: Souvenir de Moscou; arr. (Box-folder 10/9)
        - Airs russes New York: Carl Fischer, 1929., Printed score for violin and piano, with alterations in pencil; 12 p.; Uniform title: Souvenir de Moscou; arr. (Box-folder 10/10)
      - [Unidentified]
        - [Variations. Fragment], Manuscript violin part, in pencil; [2 p.] (Box-folder 13/15)
    - Multi-Composer Collections (Box-folder 5/6-9)
      - Meisterwerke der Violine Mainz: B. Schott's Söhne, 1913., Bound volume of Kreisler transcriptions for violin and piano; 94 p.; Includes (in order): Bach, Johann Sebastian. Präludium in E dur Bach, Johann Sebastian. Gavotte in E dur Leclair, Jean Maria. Tambourin Tartini, Giuseppe. Fuge in A dur Corelli, Arcangelo. Sarabande und allegretto Rameau, Jean Philippe. Tambourin Mozart, Wolfgang Amadeus. Rondo Gluck, Christian W. Melodie Schubert, Franz. Moment musical Weber, Carl Maria von. Larghetto Mendelssohn, Felix. Lied ohne Wotte Paganini, Nicolò. Caprice no. 13 Paganini, Nicolò. Caprice no. 20 Paganini, Nicolò. Caprice no. 24 Porpora, Niccolo. Allegretto in g moll Schumann, Robert. Romanze Wieniawski, Henri. Caprice in Es dur Wieniawski, Henri. Caprice in A moll Schubert, Franz. Ballet Musik aus Rosamunde (Box-folder 5/6)
      - Transkriptionen, Bound volume of Kreisler transcriptions; 74 p.; Title taken from cover (embossed in gold): Transkriptionen; Includes (in order): Albéniz, Isaac. Tango, op. 165, no. 2; New York: Carl Fischer, 1927 Albéniz, Isaac. Malagueña, op. 165, no. 3; New York: Carl Fischer, 1927 Ravel, Maurice. Habanera (Rapsodie espagnole no. 2); New York: Carl Fischer, 1928 Falla, Manuel de. Danse espagnole de La vida breve; New York: Carl Fischer, 1926 Granados, Enrique. Danse espagnole (Spanischer Tanz); New York: Carl Fischer, 1915 Rimskii-Korsakov, Nicolai. Hymne au soleil (Sonnen-Hymne) aus der Oper Le coq d'or; New York: Carl Fischer, 1919 Rimskii-Korsakov, Nicolai. Chant hindou (Hindu Lied) aus der Oper Sadko; New York: Carl Fischer, 1919 Rimskii-Korsakov, Nicolai. Danse orientale (Orientalischer Tanz) aus Scheherazade; New York: Carl Fischer, 1922 Rimskii-Korsakov, Nicolai. Chanson arabe (Arabisches Lied) aus Scheherazade; New York: Carl Fischer, 1922 Chaikovskii, Petr Il'ich. Andante cantabile aus Quartett op. 11; Fritz Kreisler, 1925 Chaikovskii, Petr Il'ich. Humoresque; New York: Carl Fischer, 1926 Chaikovskii, Petr Il'ich. Chant sans paroles; New York: Carl Fischer, 1924 (Box-folder 5/7)
      - [Bound collection of Kreisler transcriptions], Bound collection of Kreisler transcriptions; 93 p.; Includes (in order): Schelling, Ernest. Irlandaise; New York: Carl Fischer, 1928 Scott, Cyril. Lotus land, op. 47, no. 1; New York: G. Ricordi & Co., 1922 Grainger, Percy Aldridge. Molly on the shore; Irish reel; New York: Carl Fischer, 1924. [Pasteover in Kreisler's hand.] Kreisler, Fritz, arr. Farewell to Cucullain (Londonderry air); New York: Carl Fischer, 1922 Lehár, Franz. Frasquita; New York; Carl Fischer, 1927 Heuberger, Charles. Midnight bells (from The opera ball); New York: Carl Fischer, 1923 Kreisler, Fritz, arr. Viennese popular song: The old refrain; New York: Carl Fischer,1915 Krakauer, Anton. Paradise, Viennese folk-song; New York: Carl Fischer, 1922 (Box-folder 5/8)
      - [Bound collection of Kreisler transcriptions], Bound collection of Kreisler transcriptions; 93 p.; Includes (in order): Foster, Stephen C. Old folks at home (Swanee river); New York: Carl Fischer, 1925 Kreisler, Fritz, arr. Paraphrase on two Russian folk songs; New York: Carl Fischer, 1925 Paderewski, Ignacy Jan. Melody, op. 16, no. 2; New York: Carl Fischer, 1923 Paderewski, Ignacy Jan. Paraphrase on Paderewski's menuet; New York: Carl Fischer, 1917 Chopin, Frédéric. Mazurka in A minor; New York: Carl Fischer, 1915 Chopin, Frédéric. Mazurka, op. 33, no. 2; New York: Carl Fischer, 1923 (Box-folder 5/8)
      - [Bound volume of Kreisler transcriptions], Bound volume of Kreisler transcriptions; 70 p.; Includes (in order): Balogh, Ernö. Caprice antique; New York: Carl Fischer, 1924 Chaikovskii, Petr Il'ich. Chanson sans paroles; New York: Carl Fischer, 1924 Poldini, E. Dancing doll (Poupée valsante); New York: Carl Fischer, 1924 Balogh, Ernö. Dirge of the north; New York: Carl Fischer, 1924 Chopin, Frédéric. Mazurka, op. 33, no. 2; New York: Carl Fischer, 1923 Dawes, Charles G. Melody; Chicago: Gamble Hinged Music Co., 1912. [Orchestration by Adolf G. Hoffmann; pasteover by Kreisler.] Paderewski, Ignacy Jan. Melody, op. 16, no. 2; New York: Carl Fischer, 1923 Heuberger, Charles. Midnight bells (from The opera ball); New York: Carl Fischer, 1923 Grainger, Percy Aldridge. Molly on the shore; Irish Reel; New York: Carl Fischer, 1924 Dvorák, Antonin. Negro spiritual melody (from the Largo of the New world symphony); New York: Carl Fischer, 1924 Logan, Frederic Knight. Pale moon, Indian love song; Chicago: Forster Music Publisher, 1923 (Box-folder 5/9)
      - [Bound collection of Kreisler transcriptions], Bound collection of Kreisler transcriptions; 93 p.; Additional titles not transcribed by Kreisler; Includes (in order): Roeder, Edward. Wooden shoe dance, op. 2; Chicago: Gamble Hinged Music Co., 1923 Dawes, Charles G. Melody; orchestration by Aldof G. Hoffmann; Chicago: Gamble Hinged Music Co., 1912. [Pasteover and annotations by Kreisler.] Renk, Fritz. To a pickaninny; Chicago: Gamble Hinged Music Co., 1924 Korngold, E. W. Tanzlied des Pierrot, aus der Oper Die tote Stadt; Mainz: Schott's Söhne, 1920 (Box-folder 5/9)
- Writings, 1845-1966 (Box 14)
  Writings, sketches and notes of Fritz Kreisler.
  Arranged by subject or title.
  - [History of Schumann's Fantasy, Op. 131], Holograph description of the history of Schumann's Fantasy, Op. 131 (also two typescript copies) (Box-folder 14/1)
  - [Franz Rupp], Holograph statement about Franz Rupp (Box-folder 14/1)
  - Kreisler - On Relativity in Music, Transcript of interview with Kreisler, 1955. (Box-folder 14/1)
- Correspondence (Box 14)
  The Correspondence series is arranged into three subseries: Letters received by Fritz Kreisler; Letters sent from Fritz Kreisler; and General Correspondence. The General Correspondence subseries is represented by letters received by and sent from the following: American Federation of Musicians; Thomas E. Dewey; Harriet Kreisler; Charles Foley; Louis Spohr; Sylvia Voorhees.
  The series is arranged into three subseries: Letters received by Fritz Kreisler; Letters sent from Fritz Kreisler; and General Correspondent. Arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Letters from Fritz Kreisler to the following: (Box-folder 14/2-15a)
    - American Federation of Musicians (Box-folder 14/2)
    - Churchill, Sir Winston (Box-folder 14/3)
    - Foley, Charles (Box-folder 14/4)
    - Grentzer, Rose Marie (Box-folder 14/5)
    - Holt, Harold (Box-folder 14/6)
    - Mackie, Lawrence and Harold Holt (Box-folder 14/7)
    - Magill, Wallace (Box-folder 14/8)
    - Music Table, Moscow (Box-folder 14/9)
    - Prueses, Herr (Box-folder 14/10)
    - Speyer & Co. (Box-folder 14/11)
    - Spivacke, Harold (Box-folder 14/12)
    - Strok, A. (Box-folder 14/13)
    - Victor Talking Machine Co. (Box-folder 14/14)
    - Voorhees, Sylvia (Box-folder 14/15)
    - Widor, C. M. (Box-folder 14/15a)
  - Letters from the following correspondents to Fritz Kreisler: (Box-folder 14/16-40)
    - Abell, Arthur (Box-folder 14/16)
    - Archbishop of Laodicea (Box-folder 14/17)
    - Barbirolli, Sir John (Box-folder 14/18)
    - Berry, Mildred R., Access point(s): Mrs. George M. Berry (Box-folder 14/19)
    - Bruch, Max (Box-folder 14/20)
    - Casals, Pablo (Box-folder 14/21)
    - Choate, Robert A. (Box-folder 14/22)
    - Dorian, Jean Pierre (Box-folder 14/23)
    - Friedensberg, Dr. Ferdinand (Box-folder 14/24)
    - Kennedy, John D. (Box-folder 14/25)
    - Kyogoku, Takatoshi (Box-folder 14/26)
    - Lampe, Jacob E. (Box-folder 14/27)
    - Lincoln Center for the Performing Arts (Box-folder 14/28)
    - Oistrakh, David (Box-folder 14/29)
    - Oosterzee, S. van (Box-folder 14/30)
    - Rose, Billy (Box-folder 14/31)
    - Sanger, Eleanor M. (Box-folder 14/32)
    - Schang, F. C., III (Box-folder 14/33)
    - Sell, K. G. (Box-folder 14/34)
    - Steinway Artists Centenary Committee (Box-folder 14/35)
    - White, Clarence Cameron (Box-folder 14/36)
    - Unidentified (Box-folder 14/37)
    - Telegrams sent to Fritz Kreisler on the occasion of his 75th birthday (1950) (arranged alphabetically by correspondent) (Box-folder 14/38-40)
  - General Correspondence (Box-folder 14/41-65)
    - American Federation of Musicians (Box-folder 14/64)
    - Dewey, Thomas E. (Box-folder 14/65)
    - Kreisler, Harriet, 1948-1963, undated (Box-folder 14/41)
    - Foley, Charles (Box-folder 14/42-59)
    - Spohr, Louis (Box-folder 14/66)
    - Voorhees, Sylvia (Box-folder 14/60-63)
- Performance Materials (Box 15)
  Performance materials related to Fritz Kreisler's career, music and performances.
  Arranged by genre.
  - Concert itineraries (1927-1949, undated) (Box-folder 15/1-3)
  - Scripts for "The Telephone Hour," a Bell Telephone System production for broadcast on WNBC (Nov. 28, 1949 and Mar. 6, 1950) (Box-folder 15/4)
  - Promotional material and catalogues for Kreisler performances and recordings (printed) (Box-folder 15/5)
  - Press releases (typescript, 1945-1946, undated) (Box-folder 15/6)
  - Programs: Printed (1917-1961, undated) (Box-folder 15/7-10)
  - Programs: Typescript and handwritten (1939-1949, undated) (Box-folder 15/11)
  - Copyright and publication information (in the hand of Fritz Kreisler) (Box-folder 15/12)
- Clippings, 1910-1969 (Box 15)
  Clippings from periodicals and other publications related to Fritz Kreisler's compositions, performences, and life.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - 1910-1930 (Box-folder 15/13)
  - 1940s (Box-folder 15/14)
  - 1950s (Box-folder 15/15)
  - 1960s, undated (Box-folder 15/16)
- Photographs, 1845-1966 (Box 16, 24)
  Portrait and personal photographs.
  Arranged by format and subject.
  - Mounted and oversize:
    - Kreisler alone (Box 24)
    - Kreisler with others (Box 24)
    - Samuel Severin Kreisler (father) (Box 24)
    - Harriet Kreisler (wife) (Box 24)
    - Kreisler's funeral (Box 24)
  - Standard sizes:
    - Kreisler alone (Box 16)
    - Kreisler with others (Box 16)
    - Ein Märchen aus alten Zeiten (photo album from Hilde & Louis Lochner) (Box 16)
    - Violin, bow, and score (Box 16)
    - Josef Hofmann (Box 16)
- Honors & Awards, 1875-1962 (Box 16, 25 (oversize))
  Honors, citations and awards of Fritz Kreisler.
  - Honors and citations, arranged chronologically (Box 16, 25 (oversize))
- Financial Papers, 1875-1962 (Box 16)
  Financial papers of Fritz Kreisler.
  Arranged by subject.
  - Documents and correspondence relating to violins purchased, owned and sold by Fritz Kreisler (1925-1960, undated) (Box 16)
  - Account book itemizing expenses and income from Kreisler's South American tour in 1935, including entries for Brazil, Argentina, and Uruguay (Box 16)
  - Documents pertaining to the charitable activities of Fritz and Harriet Kreisler (1923-1949, undated) (Box 16)
  - Resumen de cuentas del resultado de los conciertos realizados por Fritz Kreisler durante los meses de Mayo y Junio 1935 (Summary of accounts resulting from concerts performed by Fritz Kreisler during the months of May 1935 and June 1935) (Box 16)
- Legal Documents, 1875-1962 (Box 16)
  Personal documents of Fritz Kreisler related to citizenship, social security, and contracts.
  - Citizenship documents, dated 1941 and 1960 (Box 16)
  - Contract between Kreisler and Houghton Mifflin Company for the book Four weeks in the trenches: The war story of a violinist, dated March 3, 1915 (Box 16)
  - Contract between Kreisler and Iola B. Ingalls for a concert at the New Princess Theatre of Honolulu on April 8, 1925 (Box 16)
  - Social Security Administration, Certificate of Social Insurance Award, dated August 18, 1953 (Box 16)
- Miscellany, 1875-1962 (Box 16)
  Typescript and printed miscellanea.
  Arranged by general folder heading.
  - Typescript and printed miscellanea (Box 16)
- Louis Lochner Papers, 1875-1962 (Box 17-23, 25 (oversize))
  The papers that journalist Louis Lochner (1887-1975) donated to the Library in 1960 are divided into two categories: those relating directly to Kreisler, and those pertaining to Lochner's 1950 biography, Fritz Kreisler. Kreisler's papers include letters, legal documents, and honors, as well as writings, programs, press releases, and clippings about Kreisler. Lochner's own papers in the collection consist of notes and corrections for his biography, relevant correspondence, and other miscellaneous source material.
  Arranged by format.
  - Fritz Kreisler Materials
    - Writings by Kreisler (Box 17)
    - Music of Kreisler: Songs to thee, Wisconsin (ed. Robert Foss, [1949]), containing Kreisler's Pioneers of Wisconsin [and] Valiants of Wisconsin (Box 17)
    - Correspondence
      - Letters from Fritz Kreisler to Louis Lochner (Box 17)
      - Letters from Fritz Kreisler to others (Box 17)
    - Writings about Kreisler:
      - Ewen, David. L'Amico Fritz (Box 17)
      - Lochner, Louis. Fritz Kreisler [partial]; typescripts; speeches (Box 17)
      - Smith, Beverly. He plays on the world's heartstrings (Box 17)
    - Programs (1946-1951, undated) (Box 17)
    - Press releases (typescript) (Box 17)
    - Promotional material (printed) (Box 17)
    - Photographs (Box 17)
    - Clippings (1914-1958, undated) (Box 17)
    - Honors and awards (Box 17)
    - Legal documents (Box 17)
    - Rare early books and manuscripts collected by Fritz Kreisler (Parke-Bernet Catalogue for 1949 auction), Four additional Parke-Bernet auction catalogues can be found at the bottom of box 23. (Box 17, 23)
  - Lochner materials re: Fritz Kreisler
    - Correspondence between Louis Lochner and the following:
      - Bagarotti, Giovanni (Box 18)
      - Bauer, Harold and Ethel (Box 18)
      - Cuningham, Charles E. (Macmillan Co.) (Box 18)
      - Doubleday & Co., Inc. (Box 18)
      - Ewen, David (Box 18)
      - Garrison, Elsie (Box 18)
      - Hauschild, Rudolf (Box 18)
      - Kilenyi, Edward (Box 18)
      - Kreisler, Fritz and Harriet (Box 18)
      - Laerum, Augusta Posselt (Mrs. Henrik Laerum) (Box 18)
      - Lamson, Carl and Helen (Box 18)
      - Macmillan (misc.) (Box 18)
      - Menuhin, Moshe (Box 18)
      - Milstein, Nathan (Box 18)
      - Nack, H. R. (Box 18)
      - New York Herald Tribune, Editor (Box 18)
      - Numano, A. S. M. (Box 18)
      - Oursler, Fulton and Grace (Box 18)
      - Patterson, Virginia (Box 18)
      - Pistor, Friederike Henriette (Box 18)
      - Posselt, Willy (Box 18)
      - Raucheisen, Michael (Box 18)
      - Renter, Paul (Box 18)
      - Roden, Max F. (Box 18)
      - Waters, Edward N. (Library of Congress) (Box 18)
    - Letters re: gathering information for Fritz Kreisler (Box 18)
    - Letters re: permission to cite other sources in Fritz Kreisler (Box 18)
    - Letters of appreciation and acknowledgment (arranged alphabetically) (Box 18)
    - Letters re: errors in Fritz Kreisler, with Lochner replies (Box 19)
    - Letters re: foreign translation and publication of Fritz Kreisler (Box 19)
    - Miscellaneous (arranged alphabetically by correspondent) (Box 19)
  - Lochner notes for the preparation of Fritz Kreisler
    - "Master file" [754 p., manuscript and typewritten, with clippings, programs, and other attachments] [see also oversize box 25 for large clippings] (Box 19, 25 (oversize))
    - "Leftovers for F. K." [misc. handwritten notes, typed pages, clippings, etc.] (Box 19)
    - Loose notes in Kreisler's hand (Box 19)
    - Lochner notes for interview with Kreisler (Box 19)
  - Notecards [3 x 5, in two sections: 1) organized by chapter, and 2) arranged aphabetically] (Box 20)
  - Manuscripts of Fritz Kreisler
    - Our Fritz Kreisler [typewritten, 357 p.] (Box 21)
    - Our Fritz Kreisler [typewritten, 550 p.] (Box 21)
    - Fritz Kreisler [typewritten, 450 p. (plus partial appendices); (on box): Approved by Harriet and Fritz Kreisler] (Box 22)
  - Additional materials for Fritz Kreisler
    - Foreward to (and comments on) German translation (Box 22)
    - Table of contents and List of illustrations (Box 22)
    - Works list (Box 22)
    - Footnotes and bibliography (Box 22)
    - Discography (Box 22)
    - Index (Box 22)
    - Errata (Box 22)
  - Publicity for Fritz Kreisler (Press releases, advertising, articles, interview transcripts, etc.) (Box 22)
  - Publisher's materials (Complementary copy receipts, author's biographical note, etc. (Box 22)
  - Miscellanea
    - Kreisler's 75th Birthday (1950) - (Correspondence, lists of congratulators, etc.) (Box 22)
    - Miscellaneous (printed and typescript) (Box 22)